杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 接下来我们要做的是我们已经有了语法
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Next thing that
we want to do is we've got syntax
这是一个非常高级的特性
highlighting working, but
a really advanced feature of React and
我们可以用 MDX 做的事情是我们可以使我们的语法突出显示块,
something that we can do with MDX is we
can make our syntax highlighted blocks,
显示预览，然后不仅显示预览，但使该预览可编辑。
show a preview and then not only show
a preview, but make that preview editable.
所以如果我们想说构建一个组件库并展示一个按钮。
So if we wanted to say build a component
library and show off a button.
我们希望能够编辑的地方，按钮，并看到结果就在那里。
We wanna be able to edit that button in
place and see the result right there.
这是一个非常好的方法，如果您正在编写文档，让人们尝试和
It's a really good way, if you're writing
documentation to let people try out and
不需要设置 API 就可以体验到 API 的工作方式
experience the way that the API of
something works without having to set up
锅炉模板。
the boiler plate for it.
所以这是一个非常好的特性，幸运的是
So this is a really nice feature and
fortunately
的团队已经在这方面做了大量的工作。
the team at Formidable Labs has all
ready done a bunch of work on this.
所以我们要用一种叫做现场反应的东西。
So we're gonna be using
something called react live.
所以要做到这一点，我们可以直接进入我们的代码
So to do that we can just
jump right in to our code and
比如纱线工作室盖茨比，主题文件。
say yarn workspace gatsby-theme-docs.
我们要加入反应-生活，它与所有的东西，我们所需要的
We're gonna add react-live, and it comes
with all the things that we need so
我们不需要增加任何附加的依赖项。
we don't have to add any
additional dependencies there.
现在我们已经有了现场反应，我们可以使用它，我们只是抓住它。
Now that we've got react live,
we can use it and we just grab it in.
在这个底部，我们将得到现场供应商。
Right at the bottom here,
we're going to get the live provider.
因此，反应现场使用上下文，我们将访问上下文
So react live uses context and
we're going to access that context
我们可以通过一些子组件访问它们,
to get our stuff and we access
that through a few sub components,
实时编辑器，人们可以在这里编辑代码。
the live editor, which is where
people will be able to edit the code.
一个实时的错误，以防代码是无效的，并且是一个我们可以看到的生活预览
A live error in case the code is not
valid and a life preview where we can see
结果将从 react live 进口。
the results and
that will be imported from react live.
我们需要的另一样东西是一个显微镜。
And the other thing that we're
going to need is a scope.
所以反应生活将允许我们在范围内使用不同的组成部分。
So react live will allow us to use
different components in the scope.
这样我们就不必在使用它们的任何时候导入它们
And that way we don't have to import
them anytime that we use them and
如果我们要展示一个组件库，这会让它再次变得非常方便。
that makes it really handy again if
we're showing off a component library.
人们不应该知道图书馆是如何建立的
People shouldn't have to know
how the library is set up we
应该只能说嘿，尝试添加一个按钮，然后当他们添加按钮
should just be able to say hey, try adding
a button and then when they add the button
组件它只是工作，他们不应该有导入按钮或任何东西。
component it just works they shouldn't
have to import button or anything.
因此，我们可以导入一个作用域，或者只定义一个空对象
So to do that we can import a scope or
we can define just an empty object and
添加东西是必要的，因为这是一个主题和
add things to it is needed,
because this is a theme and
因为我们希望人们能够轻松地修改这个。
because we want people to be
able to easily modify this.
我们要做的就是从盖茨比插件主题中取出一页
What we're gonna do is take a page out
of Gatsby plugin theme new eyes book and
我们要在源根上创建一个范围文件。
we're gonna create a scope
file at the source root.
这样就很容易覆盖,
And that way it'll be easy to override,
容易添加自己的组件到现场编辑的范围。
easy to add in your own components
to the scope for live editing.
因此，为了做到这一点，我们将直接跳转到这个源文件夹。
So to do that, we'll just jump
right into this source folder.
我要创建一个名为 scope.js 的文件
And I'm gonna create
a file called scope.js and
它就生活在源头。
it lives right at source root.
所以 source.scope.js。
So source.scope.js.
在它里面，我们只要输出一个空对象
And inside of it,
we're just gonna export an empty object
因为默认情况下，我们没有任何作用域。
because by default we don't
have anything in scope.
我们的主题里不会有自定义组件。
We're not gonna have custom
components coming out of our theme.
但是在这里，我们要导入显微镜，然后从显微镜中得到它。
But then over here, we're gonna import
that scope and we'll get it from scope.
然后实现这个,
And then to implement this,
好的是我们已经准备好了，我们需要的大部分代码字符串。
what's nice is we've all ready got most
of what we need with the code string.
因此，我们可以检查是否场支持反应生活。
So we can just check whether or
not the field supports react live.
我们想让这个变成可选的，对吧？
And we wanna make this optional, right?
所以我们不希望每个语法块都高亮显示,
So we don't want every
syntax highlighted block,
成为一个活生生的编辑，因为它会打破。
to become a live editable
one cuz that will break.
许多高亮显示的语法块显示部分代码、不完整代码、,
A lot of syntax highlighted blocks
are showing partial code, incomplete code,
伪代码，导入没有实际定义的东西
pseudo code, things where the imports
aren't actually defined and
如果我们只是释放那种力量，总是试图活在编辑的世界里，那就太混乱了。
that would be chaos if we were to just
unleash that, always trying to live edit.
我们要用一个属性来配置它。
So we're gonna make this
configured by a attribute.
我们要做的就是检查代码是否支持
And the way that we'll do that is that
we're going to check if code props
有一个反应现场属性
has a react live attribute on it, and
如果是这样，我们将返回一组不同的代码
if so, we're gonna return
a different set of code and
默认情况下，它会使用棱镜。
by default then, it'll use the prism.
所以我们得到了三个潜在的结果，如果没有特定的语言，我们只是使用
So we've got three potential outcomes, if
there's no language specified we just use
一个普通的旧标签和输出，一个包含所有道具的标签。
a regular old pre tag and output, a pre
tag with whatever props were supplied.
如果没有实时反应标记，我们将输出棱镜反应渲染。
If it's not marked with react live,
we're gonna output the prism react render.
如果标记为现场反应，我们将建立我们的现场供应商。
If it is marked with react live,
we're gonna set up our live provider.
在里面，我们要使用代码字符串的代码。
And inside of it,
we're gonna use the code of code string.
我们要设置的范围，这是我们的范围文件，因为我们
We're gonna set the scope and
that's our scope doc which as we
定义它，它是一个空对象。
have currently defined it,
it's an empty object.
然后我们要设定一个主题
And then we're gonna set a theme and
我们可以使用与棱镜相同的主题
we get to use the same theme as
the one that we're using in prism
反应渲染，这是真正方便，因为我们不必改变的东西。
react render which is really handy
because we don't have to change things.
我们只需导入一个主题，它就能正常工作。
We just import one theme and
it just works.
所以我们不需要做太多的工作，因为
So then we don't have to
do much with these because
我们把所有的东西都放到供应商那里。
we're putting all of that
stuff into the provider.
这意味着代码字符串、范围以及所有这些都可以通过
That means that the code string, and the
scope, and all of that is available via
这意味着我们可以直接跳过其他的部分
context, which means that we can
just drop in the rest of these
而不需要做一堆编辑，或者多次通过这些问题。
without having to make a bunch of edits or
pass those probs multiple times.
在 LivePreview 上，我想添加一点样式。
On the LivePreview,
I wanna add a little bit of styling.
让我们把这个加进去。
So let's add that in.
我想做的是，只是因为预览默认是只是种
What I wanna do is, just because the
preview by default is gonna be just kind
砸在了代码锁的底部。
of smashed against
the bottom of the CodeBlock.
所以我想把它周围的边界，只是做一点额外的和
So I wanna put a border around it and
will just do a little bit extra and
给我们一些模式。
give us some pattern.
让我们开始我们的边界，这是要访问的主题对象。
So let's start our border and
this is gonna access the theme object.
做一个像素的固体和
Do one pixel solid and
我们设置成主题，色彩，静音。
we will set it up to
be theme.colors.muted.
我们还要给它加上四个填充物，在很多情况下,
Also we gonna give it padding of four and
in a lot of cases,
你会有一段或者一个 h1之类的
you'll have like a paragraph or
a h1 or something like that and
会有很多高边距，看起来有点傻。
that'll have a lot of top margin
that will look a little goofy.
所以我会瞄准里面的第一个孩子
So I'm just gonna target
any first-child inside
然后将边距顶部设置为零。
of our preview and
just set the margin top to zero.
最后，如果有人想通过
And finally, to make this easy to target
if, if someone wants to override it via
主题 ui，我们要设置一个变体，我们称之为现场反应。
theme ui, we're going to set a variant,
and we'll just call it react live.
所以现在它是以主题为目标的
So now it's targetable in theme
而不需要使用这个特定的组件。
ui without having to mess with
this particular component.
所以这实际上是所有需要的，让这个运行。
So that is actually all that's
required to get this running.
为了测试它，让我们启动服务器。
So to test it out, let's start the server.
因此，我们将做纱线工作空间主题开发。
So we'll do yarn workspace
theme-dev develop.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们将在开始检查它是否没有破裂
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And we'll just check
at the beginning that it didn't break
任何事。
anything.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，成功了。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, successful.
好吧。
Okay.
而且它正在发挥作用。
And it's working.
我们有高亮显示的语法博客，我们有普通的老博客,
We've got our syntax highlighted blog,
we've got our plain old blog,
现在我想添加一个现场编辑的博客。
and now I want to add a live edited blog.
所以让我们从这里开始
So let's jump in here and
我们将再次打开主题 dev docs 索引,
we're gonna open up the theme
dev docs index again,
我要去买点 JSX 然后
and I'm gonna drop in some JSX and
我要以市场作为反应现场。
I want to market as react live.
这是我们的现场编辑。
So this is going to be our live editor.
为了让事情简单化,
And to make things simple,
我只需要导出一个组件，这个组件将会有一个 div。
I'm just going to export a component
that component is gonna have a divinate.
我们将加一个 h 2。
We will add an h2.
我们会说，一个按钮，然后让我们也添加这个按钮。
We'll say, a button and
then let's also add that button.
我们会给它一个点击处理程序，因为我们没有编写一个真正的按钮,
We'll give it an on click handler and
because we're not writing a real button,
我们只要确保你点击它时，它会告诉我们发生了什么事。
we'll just make sure it tells us that
something happened when you click it.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，我们已经有了我们的按钮。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay,
so we've got our button.
我们已经开发了一些 jsx 从我们的反应现场，所以应该发生的是当我
We have exploited some jsx from our react
live and so what should happen is when I
翻到页面，我们应该看到的不仅是高亮显示的语法
flip over to the page, we should be
looking at not only a syntax highlighted
块与这个代码在它，但也是一个工作预览，所以让我们给它一个尝试。
block with this code in it, but also
a working preview so let's give it a shot.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 嘿，看那个。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Hey, look at that.
现在如果我想编辑它，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们
And now if I want to edit it,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We
可以实时进行编辑，而且还能正常工作。
can make those edits in real-time and
they just work.
所以这是一个非常有效的方法
So this is an extremely powerful way for
我们可以利用页面的交互性。
us to tap into
the interactivity of a page.
因为我们把这个放在一个主题里,
And because we put this in a theme,
当你把这个安装在网站上的时候，它就能正常工作了。
it's going to just work when
you install this on a site.
所以任何想要使用这个主题的人都可以添加这个反应现场
So anyone who wants to use this theme
will be able to add that react live
属性到他们的代码块，并获得一个实时预览，可编辑的实时预览。
attribute to their code blocks, and
get a live preview, editable live preview.
既然这样说，我想我们的主题完成了。
So, with that being said, I think
we're good to call our theme finished.
所以让我们加上所有的东西，看看我们在哪里。
So let's add everything,
check where we are.
所以我们加入了 React live dependency,
So we added the React live dependency,
设置代码组件使用它设置范围，这样我们可以轻松地影子什么
set up the code component to use it set up
scope so that we can easily shadow what
可以在 React live 中使用，然后修改 index.mdx 来使用它。
components are available in React live and
then modified index.mdx to use it.
所以让我们承诺这个改变。
So let's commit that change.
添加实时编辑支持。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Add
live editing support.
好的，我们会把它推上去。
Okay, we'll push that up.